Contact

966546611140 (Mobile) sultanzabar@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/sultan-alsadi (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Project Management

Windows Server

Data Center

Teamwork

Problem-Solving

Languages

Arabic (Native or Bilingual) English (Full Professional)

Certifications

Microsoft Certified: Security, Compliance, and Identity Fundamentals

Project Management Professional (PMP)®

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals

Education

Bachelor's degree | Majmaah University جامعة المجمعة 2012

Sultan Alsadi.

Senior System Administrator | PMP | Solution Architect | Data Center | Windows Servers | IT Risk | DR & BR | #CyberSecurity

Riyadh, Saudi Arabia

Summary

I am a bachelor's degree holder in computer science & information in information technology. A self-motivated

individual who works hard to achieve goals given in accordance with specific roles. An efficient member of a team with excellent problem-solving attributes.

Seasoned System Administrator with 11 years of background in Information Technology. Progressive experience It is marked by continuous contributions above and beyond requirements. Career achievements in large-scale software Deployments, network build-outs, and data security.

In a nutshell, together, we shall transform your business through the power of people, processes, technology, and Innovation.

Experience

King Saud Medical City

Senior System Administrator August 2016 - Present (7 years 10 months)

Riyadh, Saudi Arabia

Design, install, and configure internal and customer-facing servers, network devices, and firewalls.

- # Proactively manage and maintain server, network, and firewall systems
- # Administer and support core Microsoft, Cisco, Citrix, and VMware technologies
- # Develop and implement project plans, risk assessments, and contingency plans
- # Design and implement monitoring, configuration management, and reporting functions that will make
- a hands-off environment
- # Define and document best practices and support procedures
- # Provide after-hours support for Infrastructure related emergencies as well as occasional weekend

maintenance

Maintain inventory and asset configuration documentation

Assist with hardware, firewall, telecom, and software vendor evaluation, recommendation and

negotiations

Mentor/cross train team members on existing and new technologies #
Carry out special tasks at Management's direction
Interact with customers and staff at the technical level, as required.

Other duties as assigned.

Saudi Electronic University

Technical Support Specialist September 2014 - September 2016 (2 years 1 month)

- Providing technical support to all categories of beneficiaries, including students, employees, and faculty members, and I work to perform the tasks
- Work and training on computer uses and applications.
- Receiving technical problems from university employees and fixing them or referring them to the competent authority.
- Providing and maintaining all computer and information technology equipment. E. Training all agency coordinators on the electronic support system. Work on developing the beneficiary support department.
- .Downloading the applications needed by university employees on computers.
- Creating sharing files for secret departments and colleges and facilitating the sharing of information among them. Any other duties assigned by His Excellency the Dean of Information Technology.
- Working as a support system manager (assigned) and the tasks are:
- E-Work on developing the electronic ticketing system (support).
 Communicate with the support company operating the system and submit reports. E. Create groups and add users to each group with permissions.
 Periodic meetings to raise the level of the system. Submitting the required periodic reports to the Director of Applications Management weekly and any other duties assigned by His Excellency the Dean of Information Technology.
- During his work period, we noticed his outstanding performance and sincerity in work.

Te Tech Information Technology Specialist February 2013 - July 2014 (1 year 6 months)